Guide to the Harold D. Gunn Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Provincial Files, 1908-1951, Series I
  - Benue Province
    - Tiv division
      - Mbakor district
        - Intelligence report on, undated (Box 7, Folder 155)
        - Reorganization of, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 156)
      - Mbatiav district
        - Reorganization of [by K. P. Maddocks], 1937 February 8 (Box 7, Folder 157)
        - Migration from Tiv division, undated (Box 7, Folder 158)
        - Nanev and Usar clans, intelligence report on [by K. P. Maddocks], 1936 (Box 7, Folder 159)
      - Nongov-Kambe district, intelligence report on [by K. P. Maddocks], 1934 (Box 7, Folder 160)
      - Nongov-Ndzorov district, intelligence report [by K. P. Maddocks], 1934 (Box 7, Folder 161)
      - Nongov-Saghen district, report on the reorganization of [by K. P. Maddocks], undated (Box 7, Folder 162)
        - Notes on Tiv organization [by K. Dewar], 1933 (Box 7, Folder 163)
        - Nyambuan movement in Tiv division, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 164)
        - Report on reorganization of Tiv districts [in Hausa language, report by Akiga], 1934 January 4 (Box 7, Folder 165)
      - Shengev (south) district, intelligence report on [by K. P. Maddocks], 1936 (Box 7, Folder 166)
      - Shengev (west) district, reorganization report on [by K. P. Maddocks], 1936 (Box 7, Folder 167)
      - Shitire north district, intelligence report on (by K. P. Maddocks], 1935 (Box 7, Folder 168)
      - Shitire south district, report on (by K. P. Maddocks], 1935 (Box 7, Folder 169)
      - Tiv [the], undated (Box 7, Folder 170)
      - Tiv tribal reform, 1941 May 23 (Box 7, Folder 171)
      - Tiv and Dama, ill-feelings between [general correspondence related to], 1933 (Box 7, Folder 172)
      - Tiv in Wukari, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 173)
      - Tombo (east) district
        - Intelligence report on the Mbalagh clan (of Tombo east), 1935 (Box 7, Folder 174)
        - Reassessment report [by K. T. Bryant], 1928-1929 (Box 7, Folder 175)
        - Report on the reorganization of, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 176)
      - Tombo (west clan) district
        - Tombo (west) clan, intelligence report on [by H. S. Bridel], 1937 (Box 7, Folder 177)
        - Reassessment report [by K. J. Bryant], 1928-1929 (Box 7, Folder 178)
      - Ukan district
        - Intelligence report on [by K. Dewar], 1935 (Box 7, Folder 179)
        - Ukan and Ikov clans of the Tiv tribe, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 180)
      - Utange clan, intelligence report on [by K. P. Maddocks], 1936 (Box 7, Folder 181)
      - Utiondo district, intelligence report on [by K. Dewar], 1935 (Box 7, Folder 182)
      - Utur district, reorganization report on [by R. C. Abraham], 1936 (Box 7, Folder 183)
    - Wukari division
      - Native administration, organization of, 1932-1937 (Box 8, Folder 184)
      - Notes on procedures, 1934-1937 (Box 8, Folder 185)
      - Notes on Wukari division [by P. F. Masterton-Smith], 1938 September 1 (Box 8, Folder 186)
      - Report on reorganization [by K. Dewar], 1938 (Box 8, Folder 187)
      - Donga district
        - Intelligence report on, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 188)
        - Reorganization of, undated (Box 8, Folder 189)
      - Jukon people of Wukari
        - Jukons of Wukari, undated (Box 8, Folder 190)
        - The Jukon-speaking peoples, undated (Box 8, Folder 191)
      - Kentu district
        - Assessment report [by C. W. Cole], 1934 (Box 8, Folder 192)
        - Enquiry into social organization of [by C. W. Cole], 1934 March 24 (Box 8, Folder 193)
        - Intelligence report [by C. W. Cole], 1934 (Box 8, Folder 194)
      - Takum district
        - Intelligence report, undated (Box 8, Folder 195)
        - Intelligence report [by K. Dewar], undated (Box 8, Folder 196)
        - Memorandum on reorganization of, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 197)
        - Notes and extracts from intelligence report on Takum, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 198)
    - Other districts
      - Adoka district
        - Intelligence report on clans of Adoka, Umogidi Opaha, Idoma division, undated (Box 9, Folder 199)
        - Reorganization of, undated (Box 9, Folder 200)
      - Agala ("Igala") district
        - The Agala clan, undated (Box 9, Folder 201)
        - District notebook, undated (Box 9, Folder 202)
      - Agatu district, reorganization of, 1939 January 28 (Box 9, Folder 203)
      - Akpa district
        - Akwiya clan of Akpa, 1935 August (Box 9, Folder 204)
        - Intelligence report on Akwiya clan [by R. C. Abraham], undated (Box 9, Folder 205)
        - Reorganization of Akpa district, undated (Box 9, Folder 206)
      - Awe independent district, report [by assistant district officer], undated (Box 9, Folder 207)
      - Boju district, reorganization report [by H. P. Elliott], undated (Box 9, Folder 208)
      - Egede [also called "Egedde", "Gbede" and "Yangedde"] district
        - Administration of, 1935 July 5 (Box 9, Folder 209)
        - Extracts from report by A. B. Mathews and S. A. Leslie, undated (Box 9, Folder 210)
        - Reorganization of, undated (Box 9, Folder 211)
      - Igumale district
        - Anthropological investigation of Igumale clan (Box 9, Folder 212)
        - Igumale intelligence report, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 213)
        - Intelligence report on the peoples inhabiting the Igumale district [by R. C. Abraham], 1936 (Box 9, Folder 214)
      - Ocheku district, intelligence report [by J. H. Shaw], undated (Box 9, Folder 215)
      - Oglewu and Ochobu district, intelligence report, undated (Box 9, Folder 216)
      - Okwoga district, intelligence report on [by G. D. C. Money], undated (Box 9, Folder 217)
      - Olai-Adiga-Okwoya dispute, 1940 September 2 (Box 9, Folder 218)
      - Oturkpo (also called "Otukpa" or "Orukpa") district
        - Intelligence report [by S. A. S. Leslie], 1949 September 10 (Box 9, Folder 219)
        - Intelligence report on Oturkpo clan, undated (Box 9, Folder 220)
        - Oturkpo clan, undated (Box 9, Folder 221)
        - Oturkpo district, undated (Box 9, Folder 222)
        - Presidency of the O[t]rukpa native court, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 223)
        - Progress report on Otukpa district reorganization, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 224)
        - Reorganization report on, 1936 October 13 (Box 9, Folder 225)
        - Report on [by D. F. Heath], 1938 August (Box 9, Folder 226)
        - Report on the reorganization of the Oturkpo district [by G. D. C. Money], undated (Box 9, Folder 227)
  - Bornu Province
    - General
      - Administration in Bornu, 1935 February 28 (Box 10, Folder 228)
      - Bornu Gazetteer, 1923 (Box 10, Folder 229)
      - Ethnological notes on Bornu Emirate, 1929 January 21 (Box 10, Folder 230)
    - Biu division
      - Report on Biu (Biyu) division, 1923 (Box 10, Folder 231)
      - Bura [Burra] district
        - Babur titles, 1935 July 5 (Box 10, Folder 232)
        - Bura organization [memorandum], 1935 (Box 10, Folder 233)
        - Notes on Babur, Bura, Hina, Jara & Nyimaltu customs [by F. Edgar], 1921 (Box 10, Folder 234)
        - Test assessment-West Bura district [by R. M. Peet], 1950 August 16 (Box 10, Folder 235)
      - Gwani district
        - Gwani fishing dispute with Kinafa, 1933 August 3 (Box 10, Folder 236)
        - Reorganization of, undated (Box 10, Folder 237)
        - Reorganization of Gwani district [see also organization of Tara tribe], 1933-1936 (Box 10, Folder 238)
      - Shani district
        - An account of Shani district and its district, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 239)
        - Report on the Shani and Shellen districts [by A.B. Mathews], undated (Box 10, Folder 240)
    - Dikawa division, Hill districts (see also Jos division of the Plateau province]
      - Intelligence report on the hill pagans of Ashigashiya and Gwiza [memorandum by the Resident of Bornu province], 1939 November (Box 10, Folder 241)
      - The pagan districts of the Dikawa division of Bornu Province, undated (Box 10, Folder 242)
      - Report on hill districts, 1927 July 30 (Box 10, Folder 243)
      - Social organization, custom and language of the hill tribes of Gwoza and Ashigashiya, undated (Box 10, Folder 244)
      - Sundry notes [on the Hill districts], 1919 October 27 (Box 10, Folder 245)
    - Fika (Potiskum) division
      - Fika assessment report, 1930 (Box 10, Folder 246)
      - Notes and extracts, 1951 February 22 (Box 10, Folder 247)
    - Other districts
      - Allagarno district, division of Allagarno district, 1924 July 25 (Box 11, Folder 248)
      - Geidam district
        - Assessment report on Geidam [by B. A. Marwick], undated (Box 11, Folder 249)
        - Geidam district report [by assistant district officer], 1935 February 28 (Box 11, Folder 250)
      - Kaga district, Kaga district assessment report [by J. M. Smallwood], undated (Box 11, Folder 251)
      - Konduga district
        - General information from a special report by J. D. Harford, 1926 (Box 11, Folder 252)
        - Report on Konduga district [by G. J. F. Tomlinson], 1916 (Box 11, Folder 253)
      - Magumeri district, Reassessment report, 1934 February-March (Box 11, Folder 254)
      - Marghi district
        - Marghi district assessment [by C. W. Rowling], undated (Box 11, Folder 255)
        - Notes on the Marghi tribe, undated (Box 11, Folder 256)
  - Ilorin Province
    - General
      - Ilorin Province: final installment, notes from Borgu division, 1950 October 28 (Box 12, Folder 257)
      - Ilorin and other Yoruba in the northern province: tribal and sub-tribal groupings and demography, undated (Box 12, Folder 258)
      - Ilorin Province village administration [see also Kabba province], 1930 (Box 12, Folder 259)
      - Kambari, the [also known as Kamberri, Kambali and Kamberawa], undated (Box 12, Folder 260)
      - Notes and brief extracts from provincial and divisional files, Kabba, Ilorin and Niger Provinces], 1950 October 13 (Box 12, Folder 261)
      - Notes on organization and procedures, undated (Box 12, Folder 262)
      - Reorganization of Ilorin town council, 1945 September 3 (Box 12, Folder 263)
      - Shongo society notes [from Ilorin provincial record book by P. M. Dwyer], undated (Box 12, Folder 264)
      - Village and district administration, undated (Box 12, Folder 265)
    - Bussa ("Bussawa" or "Bassa") Emirate (of Ilorin province)
      - Anthropological and historical report on the Bussawa, undated (Box 12, Folder 266)
      - Bassa Komo district notebook, extracts from, undated (Box 12, Folder 267)
      - Bussawa Emirate notebook, notes on organization and procedures, undated (Box 12, Folder 268)
      - History of Bussawa [by T. Hoskyns-Abrahall], 1935 May 23 (Box 12, Folder 269)
      - Reassessment report on Aliyara district of Bussa Emirate [by G. G. Grimwood], undated (Box 12, Folder 270)
      - Village areas, Bussawa and Kaiama Emirates, undated (Box 12, Folder 271)
    - Other districts
      - Ajasse district, memo by R. L. Payne, 1934 May 7 (Box 12, Folder 272)
      - Ekan district, reorganization of, 1934 March 9 (Box 12, Folder 273)
      - Ekitis district
        - Ancient organization and judiciary system of the Ekiti tribe, undated (Box 12, Folder 274)
        - A report on the Ekitis, 1934 May 4 (Box 12, Folder 275)
      - Iloffa ("Offa") district
        - Ilo (Ioffa] district, with special reference to the village administration [by E. W. Thompstone], 1936 June 2 (Box 12, Folder 276)
        - Precis of Offa ("Ioffa") areas, undated (Box 12, Folder 277)
        - Reorganization of [by R. J. Payne], 1935 September 3 (Box 12, Folder 278)
        - Reorganization of Offa ("Ioffa") district [memo by F. Daniel, Resident representative of Ilorin, 1935 November 7 (Box 12, Folder 279)
      - Owode district, Owode district gazetteer, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 280)
      - Share district, partition and regrouping of, 1933 February 15 (Box 12, Folder 281)
  - Kabba Province
    - General
      - Assessment report on the Kankada, Kupa and Egan districts of Kabba [by C. K. Meek], undated (Box 12, Folder 282)
      - Ethnographic notes on the tribes in Kabba, Owe age grade and title system, 1929 March 27 (Box 12, Folder 283)
      - Ifa in Kabba, 1927 May (Box 12, Folder 284)
      - Inheritance among the Owe of Kabba [according to the present Obaro of], 1934 (Box 12, Folder 285)
      - Kabba and Ilorin provinces, proposed amalgamation of, 1934 March 31 (Box 12, Folder 286)
      - Kabba cloth, undated (Box 12, Folder 287)
      - Notes on Kabba Province, 1950 July (Box 12, Folder 288)
      - Reorganization of Kabba, undated (Box 12, Folder 289)
      - The Yoruba clan of Kabba, 1931 March 9 (Box 12, Folder 290)
    - Other districts
      - Aworo district, transfer of Aworo district to Kabba, 1933 October 4 (Box 12, Folder 291)
      - Bassa Nge district, assessment report on [by T. F. G. Hopkins, includes Resident's covering report, see also Igala district], 1934 July 5 (Box 12, Folder 292)
      - Bassa Komo district
        - Assessment report on [by T. F. G. Hopkins, see also Bassa Nge], 1933 September 20 (Box 12, Folder 293)
        - Bass [a] Komo of Kotton Karifi district (see also Chiefdom of Koton Kirifi), 1944 January 13 (Box 12, Folder 294)
        - Bassa ("Basa"), including Bassa Komo and Bassa Kaunda [notes on nomenclature, location, population, neighboring tribes, linguistic data], undated (Box 12, Folder 295)
        - Bassa ("Basa"), undated (Box 12, Folder 296)
      - Bunu district, death of Olu Kirri, 1935 August 18 (Box 12, Folder 297)
      - Egbira ("Igbedde", "egbedde", "egede", "gbede") district [see also gbede]
        - Assessment report on the Egbira district [by D. Cator], 1917 June (Box 12, Folder 298)
        - An assessment report on the Igbedde district [by C. K. Meek], 1917 December 17 (Box 12, Folder 299)
        - Egedde and Ito districts, progress report [see also Ito tribe, Idoma division of Niger province], 1937 November 12 (Box 12, Folder 300)
        - Gbede clan, customs and social organization, 1930 March 10 (Box 12, Folder 301)
        - Historical notes on Igbirra ("egbira"), 1934 March 30 (Box 12, Folder 302)
      - Igala Ogwa district
        - Igala Ogwa district assessment report, undated (Box 12, Folder 303)
        - Notes on Igala history, rites and ceremonies, 1930 (Box 12, Folder 304)
      - Ijumu district, reorganization of, 1934 August 8 (Box 12, Folder 305)
      - Oluru district, extracts from note book, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 306)
      - Koton Kirifi (Chiefdom of), intelligent report [including Resident's cover report], undated (Box 12, Folder 307)
  - Kano Province
    - General
      - Draft notes on Achipawa and other peoples of Kano and middle Niger [for the Ethnographic Survey series], undated (Box 13, Folder 308)
      - Notes and extracts from PCJ's Kano, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 309)
      - Pagan communities in Kano province- reports on the Muguzawa and other groups [by various officers], undated (Box 13, Folder 310)
      - Village Council of Elders [memorandum], 1935 May 10 (Box 13, Folder 311)
    - Katagum Emirate
      - Notes on, undated (Box 13, Folder 312)
      - Historical notes, 1929 October 14 (Box 13, Folder 313)
    - Other districts
      - Birniwa (Sarkin Arawa) district, reassessment report on Hadejia Emirate [by V. Backhouse], 1930 July 28 (Box 13, Folder 314)
      - Dambatora district, assessment report on, undated (Box 13, Folder 315)
      - Dawaki ta kudu district
        - Assessment report [by D. F. H. MacBride], undated (Box 13, Folder 316)
        - Intelligence report on [by MacBride], 1938 (Box 13, Folder 317)
        - Reassessment [by W. H. Ramsay], undated (Box 13, Folder 318)
      - Jafun district, reassessment of [by D. C. Stewart], undated (Box 13, Folder 319)
      - Kumbotso district
        - Assessment report on, undated (Box 13, Folder 320)
        - Reassessment report of, 1932 August 16 (Box 13, Folder 321)
      - Kunya district, reassessment report on [by R. E. Beevor], undated (Box 13, Folder 322)
  - Niger Province
    - General
      - Arewa tribe, anthropological notes on, undated (Box 14, Folder 323)
      - Dakakari (Bengawa, Fakawa and Lilawa), middle Niger region [by F. P. Conant, drafts for the Ethnographic survey of Northern Nigeria series], undated (Box 14, Folder 324)
      - Gwana tribe, Illustration to notes on Jukons (Pottery) of, undated (Box 14, Folder 325)
      - Information required for the compilation of Niger Provincial Gazetteer, undated (Box 14, Folder 326)
      - Peoples of the Middle Niger Region, [bibliography, and draft notes prepared for the Ethnographic Survey of Africa South of the Sahara series conducted by the International African Institute], undated (Box 14, Folder 327)
      - The Tikar [draft notes prepared for the Ethnographic Survey of Africa south of the Sahara series conducted by the International African Institute], undated (Box 14, Folder 328)
      - Western division [of Niger province], notes and extracts, undated (Box 14, Folder 329)
    - Abuja division [emirate]
      - Economic resources of Niger Province, notes on Abuja division, undated (Box 14, Folder 330)
      - Reorganization of, 1934 August 24 (Box 14, Folder 331)
      - Niger Province notes, Abuja division, 1950 November 8-10 (Box 14, Folder 332)
    - Bida division
      - Bida city council- health, education and market committees, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 333)
      - Bishitiawagi, Katcha and Bakokma districts, a short history of the people of, undated (Box 14, Folder 334)
      - Declining population among the Nupe, 1940 January (Box 14, Folder 335)
      - Food adulteration in Nigerian markets [memo by the district officer of Bida division], 1937 October 25 (Box 14, Folder 336)
      - Gabi figures and Edegi, First King of the Nupe, undated (Box 14, Folder 337)
      - Notes on Nupe, [1939?] (Box 14, Folder 338)
      - Nupe glassworkers (masaga), undated (Box 14, Folder 339)
      - Kede district, Headship succession [among the Kede sub-tribe of Nupe], 1946 (Box 14, Folder 340)
      - Letter from Saidu Mamudu, Etsu Nupe, 1934 April 4 (Box 14, Folder 341)
      - Longer extracts- Nguru (Bedde, "Kede") tribes [by F. Edgar], 1925 May 8 (Box 14, Folder 342)
      - Salka district, anthropological and historical notes on the Kamberri of Salka [by A. B. Mathews], undated (Box 14, Folder 343)
    - Borgu division (also called "Burgawa")
      - Borgu history, 1921 (Box 14, Folder 344)
      - Borgu- Past and present [University of Ibadan, department of history, seminar on Borgu history], undated (Box 14, Folder 345)
      - Borgu division road policy, 1939 December 1 (Box 14, Folder 346)
      - Custom of the Burgawa ["Borgu"], extracts from Borgu divisional notebook, undated (Box 14, Folder 347)
      - Divisional notebook containing notes on ethnology, history, organization and procedure, undated (Box 14, Folder 348)
      - Extracts from the Secretariat minutes paper no. 24042, undated (Box 14, Folder 349)
    - Duara division
      - Baure district, reassessment report, 1925 (Box 15, Folder 350)
      - Historical notes- Duara, undated (Box 15, Folder 351)
      - Maiduwa district, reassessment report, 1925 September 29 (Box 15, Folder 352)
      - Notes on the history of Duara [by R. E. Vere-Walwyn], 1927 (Box 15, Folder 353)
      - Sandamu district, reassessment report, 1925 September 29 (Box 15, Folder 354)
      - Z-ongo district, reassessment report, 1925 September 29 (Box 15, Folder 355)
    - Gumel and Hadejia Emirates
      - Maigateri (Chiroma) district, assessement report on [by J. F. Hindle], 1948 August 21 (Box 15, Folder 356)
      - Veterinary work in Gumel and Hadejia emirates, 1932-1933 (Box 15, Folder 357)
    - Gwari native authority (also referred to as "Federation")
      - Allawa district, assessment report on [by P. M. Wande-Tetley], 1948 August 1 (Box 15, Folder 358)
      - Gb['w']ari tribe
        - Gb['w']ari, tribal and sub-tribal groupings: demography, undated (Box 15, Folder 359)
        - Gb['w']ari: tribal and sub-tribal groupings and demography [draft notes], undated (Box 15, Folder 360)
        - Gb['w']ari: demography and history [fieldwork notes collected by S. F. Nadel], 1936 April-May (Box 15, Folder 361)
        - Report on the Gwari [by A. B. Mathews], undated (Box 15, Folder 362)
        - The Gwari and Kamuku of Niger [by R. C. Abraham], undated (Box 15, Folder 363)
      - Koro district
        - Koro district of the Gwari Federation, Minna division, 1937 March 5 (Box 15, Folder 364)
        - Report on Koro tribe, undated (Box 15, Folder 365)
    - Katsina Emirate
      - General
        - Extracts & notes, 1925-193[3?] (Box 15, Folder 366)
        - History of Katsina prior to the British occupation, undated (Box 15, Folder 367)
        - Historical and Anthropological notes on the Katsinawa Laka of Niger [by A. B. Mathews], undated (Box 15, Folder 368)
        - Historique du Katsena, undated (Box 15, Folder 369)
        - Katsina Ala Town, 1936 February 24 (Box 15, Folder 370)
        - Towns and villages in Katsina emirate with over 500 inhabitants, undated (Box 15, Folder 371)
    - Gwandu division, Rejau report [by D. F. MacBride], 1936 April 1 (Box 15, Folder 372)
      - Kaita and Dankama districts, assessment report on riots of [by W. B. Nicholas], 1949 July 16 (Box 15, Folder 373)
      - Kankara district, Assessment report on [by J. E. King], undated (Box 15, Folder 374)
    - Kuta division
      - Kumuku district
        - Native courts, Kumuku tribal areas, extension of power of [by D. F. H. McBride], 1936 August 30 (Box 15, Folder 375)
        - Report on [by D. F. H. McBride], 1935 September 26 (Box 15, Folder 376)
        - Tribal and sub-tribal groupings and demography, undated (Box 15, Folder 377)
      - Tegina district, Bisalla, Chief of Tegina- proposed retirement of, 1934 October 7 (Box 15, Folder 378)
    - Lapai ("Lapawa") Emirate
      - Assessment report of [by H. R. I. Sackville-West], undated (Box 15, Folder 379)
      - Gungawa and Yaurawa (Bareshe), Bakarawa, Lopawa and Lawawa emirates [draft notes for the Ethnographic survey of Africa south of the Sahara series], undated (Box 15, Folder 380)
      - The Lapawa, historical and anthropological notes [by A. B. Mathews], undated (Box 15, Folder 381)
  - Plateau Province
    - General
      - Annual reports, reorganization, land tenure, revision of native authority ordinance and other notes, 1932-1945 (Box 16, Folder 382)
      - Gazetteer of Plateau Province, 1934 November 24 (Box 16, Folder 383)
      - The Jerewa Group [notes and drafts for the entry on "Pagan Peoples of the Plateau Area" in the Ethnographic Survey of Africa south of the Sahara series conducted by the International African Institute], undated (Box 16, Folder 384)
      - Kagoma and Jaba, extract notes and charts, 1927[?] November 21 (Box 16, Folder 385)
      - Kaje tribe
        - The Kaje and the tribal head, undated (Box 16, Folder 386)
        - Kaje miscellaneous notes and drafts, undated (Box 16, Folder 387)
      - Mama tribe, notes and diagrams of tribal and sub-tribal groupings, undated (Box 16, Folder 388)
      - Northern Nigeria, miscellaneous tribes in alphabetical order (A-K), undated (Box 16, Folder 389)
      - Northern Nigeria, miscellaneous tribes in alphabetical order (L-Z), undated (Box 16, Folder 390)
      - Northern Nigeria, list of tribes not yet located in provinces, undated (Box 16, Folder 391)
      - Pagans of south and west of the plateau, list of tribes, notes and drafts prepared for the Ethnographic Survey of Africa south of the Sahara series conducted by the International African Institute, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 392)
      - Peoples of the Plateau area of Northern Nigeria, a second draft of manuscripts and bibliographic notes used in preparing Part VII of the Ethnographic Survey of Africa series edited by Daryll Forde, undated (Box 16, Folder 393)